Dare to Make Contact
End of the Spear is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Jim Hanon.
"End of the Spear" is the story of Mincayani, a Waodani
tribesman from the jungles of Ecuador.
When five young missionaries, among them Jim Elliot and Nate Saint, are speared to death by the Waodani in 1956, a series of
events unfold to change the lives of not only the slain missionaries' families, but also Mincayani and his people.
Mincayani, played by Louie Leonardo.
Nate Saint / Steve Saint / Narrator, played by Chad Allen.
Kimo, played by Jack Guzman.
Young Steve Saint, played by Chase Ellison.
Barbara Youderian, played by Sylvia Jefferies.
Dayumae, played by Christina Souza.
End of the Spear is a 2005 American biographical adventure drama film directed by Jim Hanon,
written by Bill Ewing, Bart Gavigan and Hanon, and stars Louie Leonardo and Chad Allen.
The film recounts the story of Operation Auca, in which five American Christian missionaries
attempted to evangelize the Waodani people of the tropical rain forest of Eastern Ecuador.
Based on actual events in 1956, wherein five male missionaries were speared by a group of the Waodani tribe, it is told from the perspective of Steve
Saint (son of Nate Saint, one of the missionaries killed in the encounter), and Mincaye, one tribesman who participated in the attack.
The two formed a lifelong bond that continued
until Mincaye's death in April 2020.
The tone is emotional.